

Santosh Kumar Thammineni, Senior Associate

SUMMARY

Santosh is a Senior Associate in the Publicis Sapient Hyderabad office having **6 years** of experience in software industry. He has 4 years of experience in Data Engineering(Hadoop,Hive,Spark,SQL,Python/Scala,AWS and Azure). He also has experience in AWS and Cloud. He is preparing for AWS and Azure Certifications. He holds an M.Tech (Computer Science) degree.

He has worked with clients across different industries that includes E-Commerce, Banking. He has experience with leading global and multi-vendor teams.

WORK EXPERIENCE

18-Sep-2023 - Present Senior Associate - Publicis Sapient

Skills: Hadoop, Hive, Spark, AWS, Azure, SQL

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Recently completed PS start sessions (Induction)
- Completed Mandatory Trainings includes LinkedIn Learning and Udemy.

19-December-2022 - 5-Sep-2023

Data Engineer – ANZ

Skills: Pyspark, SQL, Hadoop, Teradata

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Worked with R&D team for solving business problems for Adhoc Requests using SQL.
- · Worked on Agile Methodolgy.
- Created pipelines to move the data from Teradata and other sources in to AWS S3.

26-April-2021 - 22-Nov-2022

Consultant(Big data) - Ernst & Young Pvt Ltd

Skills: Cloudera, Azure Blob storage, Hadoop, Hive, Spark, SQL, GIT

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Performed the Data load testing Using Shell Scripts.
- Involved in creating partitioning and bucketing of HIVE tables.
- Automated the Jobs using crontab

19-July-2017 - 22-April-2021

Software Engineer – Flooredge Solutions Pvt Ltd

Skills: Hadoop, Hive, Spark, SQL

Roles and Responsibilities:



Santosh Kumar Thammineni, Senior Associate

- Part of Building End to End Ingestion Framework using Python, Sqoop, Hive and Impala for ingesting data from Oracle to Hadoop which takes care of appropriate type casting of data types through a data dictionary, change data capture, Email Alerts, Job failure and recovery. MySQL is used for capturing the running metadata.
- Implemented framework to capture data from csv files to HDFS
- Worked on creating SQL for Transformation of data

EDUCATION

- M. Tech in Computer Science, JNT University, Hyderabad, Telangana.
- B. Tech in Information Technology, JNT University, Hyderabad, Telangana.

SKILLS

Cloud Technologies	AWS , Azure
Hadoop Technologies	HDFS, Hive, Spark(python/Scala),Cloudera
Database	MYSQL, Oracle, SQL Server, Teradata
Programming Languages	Scala, Python, SQL
IDE	Eclipse, IntelliJ, PyCharm
Version Control	GIT
Defect Tracking Tools:	Jira, Bitbucket
Domain Experience:	E-Commerce, Banking
Operating System	Windows, Linux